{
	"easy": [
		{
			"question": "Which band released the hit single “Smells Like Teen Spirit” in 1991?",
			"answer": "Nirvana",
			"options": ["Nirvana", "Pearl Jam", "The Beatles", "The Backstreet Boys"],
			"hint": "Kurt Cobain was this band’s singer."
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the capital city of Egypt?",
			"answer": "Cairo",
			"hint": "This is easy, so I'll tell you that it ain't Luxor.",
			"options": ["Cairo", "Rome", "Alexandria", "Luxor"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which planet is the largest in our Solar System?",
			"answer": "Jupiter",
			"hint": "Father Zeus!",
			"options": ["Jupiter", "Saturn", "Pluto", "Uranus"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which Mortal Kombat character is known for his famous catchphrase, 'Get over here!'?",
			"answer": "Scorpion",
			"hint": "His outfit is black and yellow and he uses a chain to grapple people.",
			"options": ["Scorpion", "Sub-Zero", "Johnny Cage", "Raiden"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which ocean is the largest on Earth?",
			"answer": "Pacific",
			"hint": "The Red Sea is not an ocean. That is all you get.",
			"options": ["Pacific", "Indian", "Atlantic", "Red Sea"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following countries had a civil war in the 20th century?",
			"answer": "Spain",
			"hint": "The movie 'Pan's Labyrinth' is set in this country during the war.",
			"options": ["Spain", "England", "Tanzania", "Japan"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following guitar brands was not founded by Leo Fender?",
			"answer": "Gibson",
			"hint": "G&L stands for George and Leo...",
			"options": ["Gibson", "Fender", "Music Man", "G&L Musical Instruments"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following cartoons did not air on the “Nickelodeon” channel?",
			"answer": "Courage the Cowardly Dog",
			"hint": "It features a dog prominently... not a robot pretending to be a dog.",
			"options": [
				"Courage the Cowardly Dog",
				"Invader Zim",
				"Spongebog Squarepants",
				"Catdog"
			]
		},
		{
			"question": "Peanuts are not *actually* nuts... They are _______!",
			"answer": "Legumes",
			"hint": "Well, they are not meat.",
			"options": ["Legumes", "Tubers", "Greens", "Meat"]
		},
		{
			"question": "André 3000, member of the rap group Outkast, is know famous for playing which instrument?",
			"answer": "Flute",
			"hint": "While he plays multiple variations of the instrument, they are typically all classified as woodwinds.",
			"options": ["Flute", "Saxophone", "Violin", "Tuba"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of following is not considered a Romance language?",
			"answer": "Basque",
			"hint": "Romance languages are descended from Latin.",
			"options": ["Basque", "Romanian", "Spanish", "Italian"]
		},
		{
			"question": "As of 2024, how many books from the mainline “A Song of Fire & Ice” series by George R.R. Martin have been released?",
			"answer": "5",
			"hint": "Do not include prequels, companion pieces, Elden Ring, or spin-offs.",
			"options": ["5", "7", "13", "4"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Eric Barone, possibly better known as ConcernedApe, is the creator of which of the following indie video games?",
			"answer": "Stardew Valley",
			"hint": "The game is not a platformer.",
			"options": ["Stardew Valley", "Celeste", "Undertale", "Risk of Rain"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following vegetables is classified as a nightshade?",
			"answer": "Eggplant",
			"hint": "While part of it can be green, it is not typically associated with that color.",
			"options": ["Eggplant", "Broccoli", "Carrot", "Celery"]
		},
		{
			"question": "What is my favorite color?",
			"answer": "I like the rainbow!",
			"hint": "Look around...",
			"options": ["I like the rainbow!", "Blue", "Pink", "Red"]
		},
		{
			"question": "What temperature does water boil at? Assume you are at sea level and the water is unadulterated. This is not a trick question.",
			"answer": "100C / 212F",
			"hint": "They are both even numbers in Fahrenheit and Celsius.",
			"options": ["100C / 212F", "93C / 200F", "110C / 230F", "76C / 169F"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following shapes does not have four sides?",
			"answer": "Heptagon",
			"hint": "I can’t help you with this one.",
			"options": ["Heptagon", "Rhombus", "Parallelogram", "Square"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which one of the following metals is liquid at room temperature?",
			"answer": "Mercury",
			"hint": "It is very toxic and was commonly used in thermometers.",
			"options": ["Mercury", "Iron", "Tin", "Cadmium"]
		},
		{
			"question": "This class in Dungeons & Dragons enters a state of rage to deal increased damage and gain more resistances.",
			"answer": "Barbarian",
			"hint": "I suppose a wizard could enter a state of rage, \nbut it strength and melee aren’t really wizard things…",
			"options": ["Barbarian", "Wizard", "Monk", "Fighter"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which was the third book in the Harry Potter series of young adult novels?",
			"answer": "Harry Potter & The Prisoner of Azkaban",
			"hint": "Robert Pattinson did not star in the film adaptation of this book.",
			"options": [
				"Harry Potter & The Prisoner of Azkaban",
				"Harry Potter & The Goblet of Fire",
				"Hairy Pothead & The Bong of Malice",
				"Harry Potter & The Transphobic Nitwit Author"
			]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following fighting game characters is from Fatal Fury?",
			"answer": "Terry Bogard",
			"hint": "Do not count guest appearances. This character is considered the protagonist of the \nFatal Fury series and one of SNK’s most iconic characters.",
			"options": ["Terry Bogard", "Heihachi", "Mario", "Ryu"]
		}
	],
	"medium": [
		{
			"question": "This rapper exposed Drake’s hidden son in the diss track “The Story of Adidon”.",
			"answer": "Pusha T",
			"hint": "He is a member of the rap group 'Clipse' alongside Malice.",
			"options": ["Pusha T", "Kendrick Lamar", "Meek Mill", "Vanilla Ice"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following is not an alternate name for a double bass?",
			"answer": "Tall Fiddle",
			"hint": "The fake name has the word fiddle in it.",
			"options": ["Tall Fiddle", "Contrabass", "Bull Fiddle", "Bass Violin"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Who was the author of “Moby-Dick” and “Bartleby, the Scrivener”?",
			"answer": "Herman Melville",
			"hint": "Give you a hint? I would prefer not to.",
			"options": [
				"Herman Melville",
				"William Faulkner",
				"Mark Twain",
				"Stephanie Meyer"
			]
		},
		{
			"question": "September 11th, 1973 was the date of a CIA-backed coup in which country?",
			"answer": "Chile",
			"hint": "The country is in South America",
			"options": ["Chile", "Philippines", "Brazil", "Argentina"]
		},
		{
			"question": "How many notes are in the chromatic scale in music theory?",
			"answer": "12",
			"hint": "Try to visualize a piano keyboard and count \nthe number of keys in the repeating pattern.",
			"options": ["12", "16", "10", "8"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which ancient Greek city was Oedipus king of?",
			"answer": "Thebes",
			"hint": "The answer is not Athens nor was this city allied \nwith Athens in the first Peloponnesian War.",
			"options": ["Thebes", "Athens", "Sparta", "Antioch"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following Chinese dynasties is considered a golden age and is famed for its cosmopolitan culture?",
			"answer": "Tang",
			"hint": "It’s not the Qing Dynasty; consider both parts of the question.",
			"options": ["Tang", "Song", "Ming", "Qing"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which one of the following jazz albums was made by Herbie Hancock?",
			"answer": "Maiden Voyage",
			"hint": "Red Clay is an album by Freddie Hubbard, although he \nalso appeared on the Herbie Hancock album in question.",
			"options": ["Maiden Voyage", "Tijuana Moods", "Red Clay", "Outward Bound"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following siege weapons featured a sling to launch projectiles?",
			"answer": "Trebuchet",
			"hint": "A battering ram doesn't really have projectiles, now does it?",
			"options": ["Trebuchet", "Catapult", "Ballista", "Battering Ram"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Who was the killer in the 1980 horror film “Friday the 13th”?",
			"answer": "Pamela Voorhees",
			"hint": "Uhhhh... last name is Voorhees?",
			"options": [
				"Pamela Voorhees",
				"Freddy Krueger",
				"Jason Voorhees",
				"Freddy Fazbear"
			]
		},
		{
			"question": "Does Dumbledore die? Does Gollum die? Is Tenet a mediocre movie at best?",
			"answer": "Yes",
			"hint": "Look, Tenet being mediocre had nothing to do with that poor cast.",
			"options": ["Yes", "What?", "Why?", "I won't answer"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Is this game scary?",
			"answer": "No",
			"hint": "Scary is not a euphemism for bad.",
			"options": ["No", "Yes", "Kinda", "Please stop"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Umami is the Japanese word for which of the five specific tastes?",
			"answer": "Savoriness",
			"hint": "Examples of umami foods include meat, fish sauce, mushrooms, \nand the god particle known as MSG.",
			"options": ["Savoriness", "Sweetness", "Bitterness", "Saltiness"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following metals is actually magnetic?",
			"answer": "Nickel",
			"hint": "Pawn shops typically test jewelry with a magnet to check authenticity.",
			"options": ["Nickel", "Gold", "Copper", "Brass"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which node became deprecated in Godot 4.3?",
			"answer": "TileMap",
			"hint": "The replacement is basically the same thing, \nbut more in line with how things typically work in Godot.",
			"options": ["TileMap", "Tween", "AnimationPlayer", "AnimationTree"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following languages is most classifiable as a Functional Programming language?",
			"answer": "Elixir",
			"hint": "All of these languages at least borrow from FP, but one is \npredominantly functional in paradigm. It isn't pure, though...",
			"options": ["Elixir", "Java", "Go", "Python"]
		}
	],
	"hard": [
		{
			"question": "Which US President entered Spanish occupied Florida  while chasing the Seminole peoples, leading to the U.S. taking over Florida?",
			"answer": "Andrew Jackson",
			"hint": "This event happened before his Presidency and \nwas not approved by Spain or the U.S. government initially.",
			"options": [
				"Andrew Jackson",
				"Abraham Lincoln",
				"James Madison",
				"John Quincy Adams"
			]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which movie features a woman in a radiator singing, 'In Heaven, everything is fine'?",
			"answer": "Eraserhead",
			"hint": "The film was directed by David Lynch and was released in 1977.",
			"options": ["Eraserhead", "Crash", "Suspiria", "House"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following is the name of a confirmed and provably real CIA operation?",
			"answer": "Acoustic Kitty",
			"hint": "There's a red herring in there. Everything is \nspelled correctly and the words matter.",
			"options": [
				"Acoustic Kitty",
				"MVUltra",
				"Operation Vulture",
				"Operation Ignition"
			]
		},
		{
			"question": "In chemistry, chirality is used to describe asymmetry of molecules. What does the greek root it is derived from mean?",
			"answer": "Hand",
			"hint": "Think about what chirality is describing.",
			"options": ["Hand", "Eye", "Person", "Voice"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which species of animal is featured in the painting 'Man Proposes, God Disposes'?",
			"answer": "Polar Bear",
			"hint": "The painting depicts an awful ship wreck.",
			"options": ["Polar Bear", "Albatross", "Golden Eagle", "Blue Whale"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which country in the Americas was the first to follow the Unite States in gaining independence from it's European colonizer?",
			"answer": "Haiti",
			"hint": "They were not supported by the USA and it \nshould not be surprising why that's the case.",
			"options": ["Haiti", "Mexico", "Colombia", "Argentina"]
		},
		{
			"question": "The movie 'A Fistful of Dollars' is essentially a remake of which Akira Kurosawa film?",
			"answer": "Yojimbo",
			"hint": "I'll rule out Ran for you. \nThat's an adaptation of 'King Lear'.",
			"options": ["Yojimbo", "Sanjuro", "Ran", "Hidden Fortress"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which of the following plays was written by Eugène Ionesco?",
			"answer": "Rhinoceros",
			"hint": "No connection to Godot, sorry...",
			"options": [
				"Rhinoceros",
				"Waiting For Godot",
				"Happy Days",
				"The Zoo Story"
			]
		}
	]
}
